

# **Muhammad Haseeb Tariq**

**Data Scientist** 

mhaseebtariq@gmail.com

[Request on LinkedIn]



Utrecht, The Netherlands



https://mhaseebtariq.com



https://github.com/mhaseebtariq



https://nl.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-haseeb-tariq-3b817260

## **ABOUT**

I believe I have the ideal mix of skills when it comes to the applied and practical sides of data science. With over 12 years of professional experience I have been a part of many successful data initiatives (and projects), but more importantly I have also had my fair share of failures. Those failures have helped me greatly in becoming a strategic thinker. I attribute the success of my career to the following two aspects:

- 1. Consciously striving to surround myself with people who are smarter than me
- 2. Getting things done despite the most unfavorable circumstances

I am currently leading the data science efforts at BrandLoyalty. I am helping BrandLoyalty set up the department of "Decision Intelligence". My main focus, thus far, has been on optimizing the operational forecasts (/decisions) with in the organization.



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Lead Data Scientist, BrandLoyalty

Feb 2019 - Present

BrandLoyalty designs, develops and implements loyalty solutions that help the world's most successful retailers to change consumers' behaviour.

- one...
- o two...
- o three...

#### Senior Data Scientist. Coolblue

Feb 2016 - Feb 2019 3 years

[TODO] Coolblue is...

- one...
- o two...
- o three...

#### Data Scientist, Convo

[TODO] Convo is...

one...

- o two...
- o three...

## Data Analyst / BI Engineer, Pring

Feb 2016 - Feb 2019 **O** 5 years 6 months

[TODO] Pring is...

- one...
- o two...
- three...



**S**KILLS

Data Science: SL, USL, NN

Machine Learning: PRD, MON, MLO



**EDUCATION** 

MSc in Advanced Computer Science (Data Science), University of Manchester, UK

Jun 2015 - Jan 2017

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science, NCBA&E Lahore, Pakistan

Jun 2015 - Jan 2017



**INTERESTS** 

**Sports** 

Squash

Cricket

Cooking



**LANGUAGES** 

English, Urdu, Punjabi, Dutch (A2 Level)